

Software Development Engineer seeking roles in Application Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Data Structures, Algorithms, Design Pattern, Java, OOPs, Agile, MySQL, C#



Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: HashedIn Technologies Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Development Engineer, Software Developer, Application Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Requirement Analysis, Data Structures, Algorithms, Design

Pattern, Java, OOPs, Agile, MySQL, C#, Spring Boot, multithreading

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

### Summary

A Software Engineer with experience in the Agile project life cycle. Experienced in the processes of Software Development, Quality Assurance and Business enhancements in a project. Driven by passion, enthusiasm and a flair for knowledge on how things work, how

things can break and how it can function better, helps me deliver the best in any given project under any domain.

# **Work Experience**

HashedIn Technologies as Senior Software Engineer Nov 2020 to Till Date

NTT DATA as Software Development Engineer -Java Jan 2019 to Nov 2020

Achievements/Tasks

Experienced in the Development and Testing (Unit and Functional) practice under the banking domain using Java, Data structures and Algorithmic concepts.

Hands on experience with Microsoft SQL Server, My SQL, Toad for Oracle.

Experienced in the Agile Methodology in SDLC such as planning, analysis

design,implementation,testing and maintenance of web based, client server and N-tier architecture

Coordinated with key stakeholders, global business and business analyst for thorough understanding, requirement gathering and progress tracking.

Knowledge of software based practices like test driven development(TDD), continuous integration and continuous deployment.

Worked on the code enhancement and improvement by reducing run time of the code with time and space complexity research and analysis.

Prepared test-case ,test-suite ,test results and traceability matrix ,executed test case documents to keep track of project deadlines and quality of result.

Took simplification initiative by creating automated test framework and script for web service testing using SOAP UI tool and selenium web driver resulting in huge cycle time reduction

Basic understanding and knowledge of REST API.

Onsite appreciation from client for showing dedication in work.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from SRM INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY in 2018

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Data structures and algorithms	
Java, Oops	
MySQL	
Microsoft SQL Server	
C, C++	
C#	
WINDOWS, LINUX	
DESIGN PATTERN	
Multithreading	

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

## **Projects**

Project Title: Creditonline

Client: Experian Credit Information Company Of India

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Aug 2020 Project Location: Norway Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 15

Project Details: Experian provides the data like credit score. It contains detailed information of your credit/Loan history including your identity information, credit accounts, loans, payments, recent enquires etc. Based on your credit score it will

show whether you are capable of taking another loan or not.

### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full time